abovethecrowd.com 1999-05-03

# CNET privacy statement

**CNET: The Computer Network**  
**Overall privacy statement**  
Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. Because we gather certain types of information about the users of CNET's network of sites, we feel you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather, how we use it, and how to correct or change it. 

**TRUSTe certification**  
[](https://www.truste.org/validate/321)This overall privacy statement verifies that CNET: The Computer Network is a member of the TRUSTe program and is in compliance with TRUSTe privacy principles. This statement discloses the privacy practices for the entire CNET network of Web sites, which includes [Browsers.com](http://www.browsers.com/), [Builder.com](http://www.builder.com/), [CNET.com](http://www.cnet.com/), [Computers.com](http://www.computers.com/), [Download.com](http://www.download.com/), [Gamecenter.com](http://www.gamecenter.com/), [News.com](http://www.news.com/), [Search.com](http://www.search.com/), and [Shareware.com](http://www.shareware.com/). 

TRUSTe is an independent, nonprofit initiative whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the principles of disclosure and informed consent. Because this site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed and audited for compliance by TRUSTe. When you visit a Web site displaying the TRUSTe mark, you can expect to be notified of: 

  1. What information this site gathers/tracks about you
  2. What this site does with the information it gathers/tracks
  3. With whom this site shares the information it gathers/tracks
  4. This site's opt-out policy
  5. This site's policy on correcting and updating personally identifiable information
  6. This site's policy on deleting or deactivating your name from its database

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to CNET ([support@cnet.com](mailto:support@cnet.com)) or TRUSTe ([www.truste.org](http://www.truste.org/)) for clarification. To return to the page you came from, please use the Back button on your browser. 

**1\. Information CNET gathers and tracks**  
CNET gathers two types of information about users: data that users provide through optional, voluntary registration on several of our sites and through optional, voluntary participation in certain contests and sweepstakes; and aggregated tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites. Such information enables us to better tailor our content to readers' needs and to help our advertisers better understand the demographics of our audience. Because CNET derives its revenue mainly from advertising, providing such aggregated demographic data is essential to keeping our service free to users. The only situation in which CNET divulges information about an individual user to a third party is with certain contests and sweepstakes\--and then, _only with the user's express consent._

CNET gathers user information in the following processes: 

**• Optional registration**  
Several CNET sites offer free, voluntary registration to users: CNET.com, News.com, and Gamecenter.com. By registering, users can enter the sites without having to log on each time; they gain access to the polling area; and they can take advantage of personalization (the ability to select content according to a user-supplied profile). 

During registration the user **is required** to supply a username, password, and email address, and must answer mandatory survey questions about age, gender, income, Internet connection, zip code, country, employment status, and other employment information. 

During registration the user **has the option** of supplying a first name, last name, and password hint. In addition, the user can opt to subscribe to various CNET electronic newsletters and to have his or her email address and/or URL appear in postings. 

**• Polling**  
Several CNET sites offer interactive polls to users so they can easily share their opinions with other users and see what the CNET audience thinks about important issues. CNET uses a system to "tag" users after they have voted, so they can vote only once on a particular question. This tag is not correlated with information about individual users. 

**• Message boards/forums**  
Users of the CNET Message Boards and of Builder.com's _Builder Buzz_ bulletin board must register separately for these services (both are free of charge). During registration the user **is required** to supply a username, password, and email address. The user **has the option** of supplying a company name. 

**• Electronic newsletters (Dispatches)**  
All the CNET sites except Search.com offer a free electronic newsletter to users. CNET gathers the email addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe. Users may remove themselves from this mailing list by following the link provided in every newsletter that points users to the subscription management page. Users can also subscribe to the newsletters at the time of registration. 

**• News.com's "Send this story to a friend" service**  
A reader can choose to electronically forward a news story to someone else by clicking the link at the top of that story. The user must provide their email address, as well as that of the recipient. This information is used _only_ in the case of transmission errors and, of course, to let the recipient know who sent the story. The information is not used for any other purpose. 

**• Surveys**  
Occasionally CNET conducts user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our advertisers and partners. We never share any of this information about specific individuals with any third party. 

**• Contests and sweepstakes**  
CNET offers contests and sweepstakes in which we request certain personal information. At a minimum, the required information includes name and email address; in some cases, the user must answer mandatory survey questions about a range of other personal data. The information gathered in the entry form is used to verify the entrant's identity, to send the entrant an email notification that their entry has been received, and to contact winners and/or prize recipients. There are two situations in which CNET will divulge this information to a third party-- _provided the user gives express consent:_

(1) A user may expressly choose to receive additional information from the contest sponsor, in which case the user's personally identifiable information is divulged to the advertiser. 

(2) Some of the contests may be hosted on the CNET site but administered by the sponsor; in such cases, the information a user provides is passed on to the third party _as long as that user gives express consent._

Because the rules and terms of each contest can vary, all information about each contest is clearly posted during the event. All contests and sweepstakes are conducted in full accordance with United States federal and state laws. 

**• Usage tracking**  
CNET tracks user traffic patterns throughout all of our sites. However, we do not correlate this information with data about individual users. CNET does break down overall usage statistics according to a user's domain name, browser type, and MIME type by reading this information from the _browser string_ (information contained in every user's browser). 

CNET sometimes tracks and catalogs the search terms that users enter in Search.com, but this tracking is never associated with individual users. 

**• Cookies**  
A _cookie_ is a small data file that certain Web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you've visited. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. CNET uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above), when you register as a CNET member, and when you click an ad: 

> **Registration:** when you register, CNET uses a cookie to store a unique, random user ID. We do not store passwords or any personal information about you. We use this ID to identify you anonymously in our database and to track the pages you visit on our site. Cookies also enable you to enter CNET sites as a member without having to log on each time, and to visit member-restricted areas of the sites. We encrypt the user ID for added security. 
> 
> **Ads:** CNET's advertising system delivers a one-time cookie to better track ad impressions and click rates.

If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. 

**You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use any CNET site.**

**2\. Use of the information**  
CNET uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience in our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users. 

  * As stated above, CNET uses information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in polls and message boards. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule (daily or weekly, depending on the newsletter), and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. CNET never shares newsletter mailing lists with any third parties, including advertisers or partners.
  * When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. CNET does not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you.
  * We track search terms entered in Search.com as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don't track which terms a particular user enters.
  * CNET creates aggregrate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs. Because CNET doesn't track the usage patterns of individual users, an advertiser will never know that a specific user clicked their ad.

**3\. Sharing of the information**  
CNET uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and help our advertisers better understand our audience's demographics. This is essential to keeping our service free. We do not share information about individual users with any third party, except in the case of some contests and sweepstakes\--and then, _only with a user's express consent._ CNET does not control the practices of our advertisers. If you have questions about how one of our advertisers uses information about you when you click their ad and go to their content, please contact them directly. 

**4\. Opt-out policy**  
CNET gives users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include: 

  * Opting not to receive our electronic newsletters when registering for a site
  * Opting not to provide certain personal information when registering for a site or when participating in some contests (see above)
  * Opting not to participate in certain interactive areas, which completely alleviates the need for any information from our users

**5\. Correct/update policy**  
CNET offers users the ability to correct or change the information collected during registration for any site (see above). The instructions for doing this can be found in our Member Services area. Users may change this information at any time and as often as necessary. Users who are experiencing problems or who have any questions about how our services work can contact us at [support@cnet.com](mailto:support@cnet.com). 

**6\. Delete/deactivate policy**  
Users may unsubscribe to any of our electronic newsletters at any time by following the instructions contained at the end of every newsletter. 

Currently, CNET does not offer users a means by which to completely delete personal information established at the time of registration for any site.
